Just hope and he will show you.
You can't look over the mountain.
Don't look over it.
About our attitude to this animal, we have
one saying that sounds like this.
In the morning I get up, I see my father,
then the horse, and then my wife and
children.
The horse stands so high.
For Turkmenistan?
For Turkmenistan.
It's very expensive.
The average price is 100,000 dollars.
There are thought to be fewer than 5,000
Akhol techies in the world, but the
president himself is said to own a herd of
seven.
several hundred.
For the President, the halteke is
something very important as a symbol for
the nation.
That's true?
Yes, yes.
We always wear it on our horses.
We have a big love for horses.
Thank you.
Wearing the traditional costume, a jacket
and hat made from sheep's wool, the
papaka, a symbol of honour and dignity.
It's really a panoply.
The great leader too never misses an
opportunity to be filmed in this outfit
and on this animal,
which links him to the mythical history of
his people.
He even broke another record in 2018.
His own akol teki, which he had trained
himself, walked on its hind legs for 4.19
seconds.
A feat that is obviously listed in the
Guinness Book of Records.
But his passion for horses almost cost him
dearly.
In 2013, a major race was organized in
which the president took part.
For once, several foreign journalists were
invited.
The great leader won, of course.
But at the end, in front of a large
audience,
dozens of men in black rushed in.
The president appeared to be unconscious.
For several seconds, the regime held its
breath.
He was taken to an ambulance.
Later he emerged apparently well
recovered.
The authorities did everything they could
to prevent the images leaking.
Everyone leaving the country was searched
at the airport.
It was a failure.
The footage went around the world.
Only the Turkmens didn't see it.
And it was obviously censored on national
television.
The instructions were to show only the
glitz and glamour.
And always, whatever happened, to praise
the dictatorship.